<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Entri.me, Specially designed courses for KEAM 2016 and 2017</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/tips.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-05-23T10:20:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>10 marks required for you to clear Kerala Entrance Exams.</title><link href="/10-marks-required-for-you-to-clear-kerala-entrance-exams.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-13T10:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Entri.me</name></author><id>tag:,2015-08-15:10-marks-required-for-you-to-clear-kerala-entrance-exams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is some news for Kerala entrance exams aspirants this year from the Commissioner of Entrance Examinations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A press release published on the official website of the Commissioner of Entrance Examinations (CEE), Government of Kerala says a student requires a minimum of 10 marks each in Paper-1 and Paper-2 by KEAM 2015, in order to qualify for inclusion in the concerned rank lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kerala Entrance exams 2015 for admission to engineering programmes is scheduled to be conducted from April 20, 2015 and April 21, 2015 and as stated in the above mentioned information, only those candidates who would secure a minimum of 10 marks in each paper will qualify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest assured you can score way more than 10 marks if you take one of our short and intelligent &lt;a href="http://entri.me/products/choose/"&gt;courses&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entrance"></category><category term="kerala"></category><category term="keam"></category></entry><entry><title>How can parents help their child crack the Kerala Entrance Examination</title><link href="/how-can-parents-help-their-child-crack-the-kerala-entrance-examination.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-23T10:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Entri.me</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-23:how-can-parents-help-their-child-crack-the-kerala-entrance-examination.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the board exams winding up and the entrance fever catching on, the pressures take a heavy toll on the student’s mind and body. It is upto the parents to ensure that while their kids spend all their energy in studying, the rest of the things are taken care of by them. As parents, at times, your role is much more important than that of the teacher in ensuring the perfect success of your child in the coming Kerala Entrance Exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://bytebucket.org/thecoderdotin/blog.entri.me/raw/61fe39067310044909603babd9cbc55f51cf3ace/content/images/2015/04/parent-child-1.jpg?token=54233cf5d784106ccf19f5ff2bd11cbea341b2ea" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we discuss the top 7 pointers on how parents can help their kids crack the Kerala Entrance Exam – &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide them with a comfortable environment
Without doubt, this goes as the first step. Only a sound mind can concentrate on any work being done, and every sound mind needs a comfortable environment to perform at its best. 
Make sure that the lighting in your child’s study room is perfect, he/she’s not disturbed by the sound of the TV, the PC is not placed in their room to avoid distraction, the room is clean and tidy, there’s drinking water placed in their room so that they do not have to visit the kitchen always etc. Ensure you give them a relaxed environment, but do not go as far as to make them feel too pampered!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure a regular Study Time Table is followed
Clearing the Kerala Entrance Exams isn’t a walk in the park. And to secure a good rank, one definitely needs to be pragmatic in their approach. If your child hasn’t already planned it out, see to it that they have a study time table put in place right upto the day of the exam. This will not only help them know where they stand in the path of preparation but also ease off stress from their minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inculcate healthy lifestyle habits
Many kids spend sleepless nights and cut down on their food intake to dedicate more time on their studies. This does more harm than good. Only a healthy body can home a healthy mind, and only a healthy mind will be able to focus while studying. Encourage your kids to eat healthy food at the right schedule and to always get a good night’s rest – not only on the day before the exam, but also on all other days. Mental fitness is not just a result of how much the body is relaxed on the day of the exam but is a cumulative outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not put undue pressure on them
The Board Exams, hectic schedules from school, even more hectic timetables from the Entrance coaching centers, all these have already turned the brain of your child in a pressure cooker situation. Refrain from pressurizing them further.
Do not compare their efforts with their peers. Each child is different and their learning capacity differs. This does not mean one kid is better than the other. So refrain from the most common mistakes of comparing them with other kids, pressurizing them into studying every minute of the day or letting out your stress on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encourage regularly
It’s not just enough to not put pressure on them, but is even more important that you encourage them regularly. Remind them that you are on their side and no matter what the outcome, they should just give their best. Most kids are afraid of their parents’ reaction about the results of the exam and tend to put a lot of pressure on themselves, whether the parents know it or not.
Make them feel comfortable about themselves and about the whole Kerala Entrance Exam process. Advice them to just give their best shot and it’s not the end of the world if their score isn’t what they hoped for. Your support will likely go further than you think in reducing their stresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure they get a dose of fresh air
Don’t keep them bundled up in a room all the time. Make sure they get out of the house to freshen their minds and body for atleast a couple of hours everyday – even the day before the exam! The freedom the body experiences at these moments goes a long way in re-boosting their minds and helps them focus better when they sit down to study next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not leave the logistical preparations for the last minute
While your kids would be busy with the preparations, and though they would also be responsible for looking into the details of hall ticket, extra pens, pencil etc, it is also your duty to get all these ready for your kids well before the due date. 
This also stands true in getting them the right text materials for their preparations. Do not wait for the Board Exams to end before you get them the specific Course Materials for preparing for the Kerala Entrance Exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus Pointer : Try out Entri.me/parents
Yes, we are blowing our own bugle with this one, but it’s only because we are super confident of how our tools helps you keep a tab on the progress of your child over a period of time, and help understand their strong points from the weak ones. Get intelligent and summarized reports of the mock tests attempted by your child, with detailed insights on the questions they spend more time on, topics they find longer to comprehend and suggestions on topics they need improvement on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone thinks it’s only the child’s efforts that land him/her with a brilliant score in the Kerala Entrance Exams. Actually, its not. It’s in fact a cumulative effort of the kid’s preparations and the parents support which determine how well the child performs. And that’s exactly why you see the parents smile brighter when their child secures that rank he/she worked so hard for.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entrance"></category><category term="kerala"></category><category term="keam"></category></entry><entry><title>Top 5 ways to prepare for your Kerala Entrance exams.</title><link href="/5-ways-to-prepare-for-your-kerala-entrance-exams.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-03T10:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Entri.me</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-03:5-ways-to-prepare-for-your-kerala-entrance-exams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have always been encouraged to ask doubts. When you ask questions in the classroom, you are modeling a process that students can and should use themselves. Developmental research suggests that this drive for explanation is, in fact, in place very early in human life. We've all experienced the endless "whys?" of three-year-olds and the downright dangerous two-year-old determination to seek out strange new worlds and boldly go where no toddler has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At entri.me we have been getting e-mails, Olark chats, Whatsapp messages and SMSes with all kinds of doubts ranging from a formula in Chemistry to admission in a college. This is why we have been working on "Doubts" and is now ready to make the first version public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubts will be closely integrated with entri.me courses. For instance you will be able to ask a doubt when you are attempting a question and get answers for it from entri.me subject experts as well as the entri.me community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking of the kind of questions that we expect, it can be obviously a subject related doubt, questions related to admission in colleges, questions about entri.me courses. We assure you that all the questions will be answered by our in-house subject experts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short no doubt will go unanswered :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="entrance"></category><category term="kerala"></category><category term="keam"></category></entry></feed>